So, your exercise is to go to the disk page and try to do what we just did, which is essentially
migrate everything that you see inside of the options, so that means data, computed, methods,
and mounted, and practice moving that all over into composition API.
First thing first, we're going to go ahead and what we need for the composition API is a setup method.
That is life cycle hook that will hold everything in here.
So, let's go ahead and just, I'm going to copy all this over, so it was my great data first.
So, inside of here, paste that over, so we have a concept, woo, that was a typo,
console, through text, and this is a ref. So, again, I'm going to import that automatically.
So, if you'll notice that in the auto-complete, if your view code is hopefully working the way I
hope it does, you'll notice that ref should show up and if you select the package, I'll show that one
more time. If you just select the top one, it's just going to do some random thing, but you'll notice
that ref here, it'll actually say that it's from the, you see that little package thing from view.
That's how you know, it's from view. Oh, that's why it's already imported.
Hang on, let me go back. I do want to make sure I show that, get that screen grab.
So, again, if I go ref, you'll see that on the right-hand side, there's that, it tells you where it's
coming from, and that's how you know you want to import it from view. So, that's how I'm doing that,
so when I hit that, it'll automatically augment my import up here. So, just know that
that's all the magic that's happening. All right, ref of string, we're good,
cons, dish list is going to be a ref of dish array, and then we just need to pass that in as an
argument, so wrap that in parentheses, and we're golden. The, why is that? They got to look
better. And then cons show new form is a ref that is a boolean, but we're going to let that
automatically infer. So, as you'll see that, we don't need to define this here. We don't
need to be like boolean, and we don't need to be like string, because it's being assumed that
that will be the case for both. All right, then let's go ahead and just start our return
object, because we want to actually expose all these, so filter text, show new form and
dish list. Great. Now, we can delete this data, data shape up here at the top.
All right, and let's keep the journey going. We have two things that are computed. So,
we're going to jump in here. Once again, this is a cons, the filter dish, and what kind of variable
is it? It is a computed variable. So, again, you'll see the view right here, hit that, and you'll
see that import here, computed right at the top, and it even alphabetically organizes it,
which is great. All right, so bump, bump, bump, there we go. We'll deal with that this is in a second.
So, then here equals computed, and then we just need to turn this into an arrow function.
And actually, small aside, that's actually one of the nice things about the
composition API is that arrow functions in options API would break the this reference
sometimes. So, you actually couldn't use arrow function within options API when defining things.
So, it's a nice thing to get back to you if you enjoy that sort of shorter syntax.
All right, so now we just need to grab anything that has this, because we know that we're using
graphs for all of it basically, and then we just need to delete it, and then replace it with dot value,
because we need to unpackage our references. So, there we go, that's good to go now, and so now we can
say filtered dish list, and then we have our number of dishes. Great.
Finally, we're almost there. We're just going to actually let's just grab all this and just
move it on in. Let's grab the methods, and then 1, 2, 3, const equals jump ahead at the arrows.
This is great. Wait, I messed up. Too far. There you go. Jump here.
Then we go 1, 2, 3 equals, then jump to the end, then that.
And then we're good to go for the most part, just have these commas to deal with.
For all this, this stuff, we can just roll this too much. 1, 2, 3, 4. I'm using Command D,
for me, this is how you select multiple things on your cursor, and then from there, 1, 2, 3,
for dot value. Save, let's good, add dish, delete dish, and hide form for the sake of being
alphabetical, and finally we have our unmounted here, and so we have on mounted, and you can see here,
it's now autocomplating with views, so I can hit enter, and once again it will automatically
import that directly from view, and then we just need to pass it in the callback function that
will run every time it hits that lifecycle hook, but we don't have this, so what do we need?
We need use route, and we'll import that from use router, and boom, again the autocomplete is one
of the best things about TypeScript to be totally honest, even if you're not annotating everything,
because that's one of the benefits of using TypeScript is that anyone who's like the library
others who went through the effort of documenting all that, you just get that for free, and so
that's another to be honest, another reason why I like to recommend, just starting out using TypeScript,
even if you're not actually applying it everywhere. Okay, unmounted, that's good, and I think
that's everything. So I had you all do that exercise for a reason, is that some of you probably
were thinking even as I was typing, you're like, wow, that's a lot of boilerplate,
particularly this thing down here. What I'm happy to tell you is that there is a better way of doing
this, which again, I wanted to show you just a full pass, so you know where all this is coming from,
we'll be showing you sort of the more common way you'll see a composition API use going forward,
and then from there we'll continue building on our knowledge for using view and TypeScript.